原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     Carolgcz  苏小黛  glida
翻译     海云生  布塔不想唱歌
校对     布塔催人泪下
时间轴   西·查  caroline  今  噃噃  壬虚浪影
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔狗粮鼻祖
小姐和流浪汉
♪ 夜晚寂静如雪 ♪
♪ Silent as the snowflake in the night ♪
♪ 神圣的夜晚 ♪
♪ Holy is the spirit of this night ♪
♪ 世界一片祥和 ♪
♪ All the world is calm and peaceful ♪
♪ 世界一片欢乐 ♪
♪ All the world is bright and joyful ♪
♪ 爱之精神  和平之子 ♪
♪ Spirit of love and child of peace ♪
我可以打开了吗
Can I open them yet?
-不行  -快点
- No. - Hurry up.
别睁眼
Keep them closed.
-是什么  -别睁眼
- What is this? - Keep them closed.
好吧
Okay.
-是什么  -不许偷看  不许偷看
- What is it? - No peeking. No peeking.
好...睁眼吧
And... Open.
真棒
Great.
你觉得我帽子还不够多
You think I need another hat?
再猜猜看
Guess again.
围巾
A scarf?
你认为我会为一条围巾让你闭眼吗
You think I'd make you keep your eyes closed for a scarf?
你这辈子一直想要的东西
What have you wanted your entire life?
除了我以外的东西
Besides me, of course.
这么谦虚  我不知道
So modest. I don't know...
小狗
A puppy!
达令  怎么样
Well, Darling, what do you think?
吉姆  它是个完美的小淑女
Jim Dear, she's a perfect little lady.
欢迎来到我们家
Welcome to the family.
这样就好了
And that should be nice.
祝你好梦
Sweet dreams.
还有这个
And one more thing.
这样应该能行
That should do it.
你这笨狗狗
You silly, silly girl.
睡个好觉  淑女
Sleep tight, Lady.
晚安  淑女
Goodnight, Lady.
别这样  别这样  别这样
No, no, no, no, no.
吉姆
Jim.
好了  过来  宝贝
All right. Come here, baby.
过来  好了  去睡觉吧
Come on. All right, go to sleep.
搞什么
What?
-你怎么搞的  -怎么这样子
- How did you do that? - How did that happen?
好了  淑女  不要
Okay, Lady, that's... No.
好了  看着
Okay, now watch.
看  这才是你睡觉的地方  好吗
See, this is where you sleep, all right?
看爸爸怎么睡的  像这样
See how daddy does it? Just like this.
看到没
See?
拜托  吉姆  看看它  让它睡这儿吧
Come on, Jim. Look at her, please, let her stay.
-好吧  就一晚  淑女  -好耶
- All right, just for one night, Lady. - Yay!
舔他  去舔他
Get him. Go, get him.
又是美好的一天  最好叫他们起床
Another perfect day. Better get them up.
有你在谁还需要闹钟
Who needs an alarm clock when they have you around?
你好啊  淑女
Oh, hello, Lady.
好了  我起了
All right, I'm up.
今天是你的大日子
Today's your big day.
淑女  我们准备一下  过来
Lady, let's get you ready. Come on.
过来  乖狗狗
Here you go. Yeah, that's a good girl.
我帮你洗干净  舒服吗
Let's get you clean. Does that feel good?
淑女
正式宣布了
Now you're official.
要不要去给乔克和老信瞧一瞧
You wanna go show Jock and Trusty?
要吗
Yeah?
我有了  我有
I got it! I got the...
项圈了
Collar.
什么
What?
是你  你要是不想惹事
You! If you don't want trouble,
我想你知道什么叫惹事
and I think you know what trouble looks like,
你最好
then you better...
希望你听明白了
I hope I made myself clear!
老信
Trusty!
老信  你在吗
Trusty? Are you over there?
老信  老信  你猜怎么了
Trusty! Trusty, guess what?
这么激动干什么
What's all the commotion?
那只老鼠回来了  你知道那只
That rat came back, you know the...
那只老鼠
The rat?
-在哪儿  -没有  其实
- Where? - No, it's actually...
-别慌  -老信  都处理好了
- Stay calm. - Trusty, it's all taken care of.
我和靠得住能闻到气味
Me and Ol' Reliable will pick up the scent.
可是他...他其实已经跑了
But he... But he's... He's gone, actually.
我跟你说  我刚刚...
Hey, guess what, okay, I just...
这事急不得
Can't rush the process.
老信  听着  我有事跟你说  乔克在哪
Trusty, focus. I gotta tell you something. Where's Jock?
她在上班
She's working.
侦查的活儿
Detective work...
那边怎么了  他们在说什么
What is going on over there? What're they talking about?
别乱动  亲爱的杰奎琳
Don't fidget, my sweet Jacqueline.
别动  再坚持一下  我们完事了
Stay still, just a little bit longer. We are finished.
你觉得怎么样  小美人  对吧
What do you think? Bellissima, huh?
好吧  你可以去跟朋友们玩了
All right, you can go play with your friends.
但是只能去五分钟  杰奎琳
But for five minutes, Jacqueline.
妈妈再去拿块新画布  五分钟就来
Mommy needs a new canvas. Five minutes!
我有好多事要做
I have so much to do.
等等我  怎么了
Wait for me! What's goin' on?
穿着这件毛衣跑过来真是个天大的错误
Sprinting in this sweater was a big mistake.
你的过错在于起先就不该穿那玩意儿
Your mistake was putting that thing on in the first place.
-狗嘴里吐不出象牙  -伙计们  伙计们
- You've got incontinence from your mouth. - Guys, guys, guys,
今天早上发生了一件非常特别的事
something very special happened this morning.
你们肯定不信
Something you won't believe.
-我有...  -你有项圈了
- I got... - You got your collar!
我有项圈了  是的  我有了
I got my collar. Yep. I got it!
淑女  这真漂亮
Oh, Lady, it's beautiful!
-我跟你说过会有的  -你说得对
- I told you it would happen. - You were right.
现在  我正式成为家里永远的一员了
Here I am, officially part of the family. Forever.
这是你应得的
You've earned it.
你知道这个项圈跟什么最配吗
You know what would go great with that collar?
-闪闪发光的头饰  -听到这个我就该走了
- A twinkly tiara to sit upon your head. - And that's my cue.
我要去追那只老鼠
I'm gonna go track that rat.
这本是你该做的事  而不是花里胡哨地打扮
Which is what you should be doing instead of playing dress-up.
是  是  老信长官
Ay, ay, Officer Trusty.
他毛都找不着
Oh, yeah, he's not gonna find anything.
-虽然他很想找  -找到大门了
- Well, not intentionally. - Found the gate.
乔克宝贝  杰奎琳
Jocky-Wocky! Jacqueline!
我的小模特儿呢
Where's my little model?
谁是这个世界上最伟大的魔术师啊
Who's the greatest magician in the world?
我得走了  祝贺你收到项圈
Well, I have got to go. Congrats on the new collar.
你真是找了户好人家  是吧
Crivens, good family you've got there, eh?
我知道  没有更好的了
I know. Really couldn't get any better.
这感觉真好
This feels nice.
只会越来越好
And it's only gonna get better.
清除路障  清除路障
Clear the line! Clear the line!
快点  继续  很好  保持住
Come on. Keep it moving! That's good. Hold it there.
卸下来  伙计们
Put it out of the wagon, boys.
-去干活  -好的  先生
- Get to work. - Yes, sir.
好  你需要搭把手吗
All right, you need a hand with that?
看起来又是美好的一天
Looks like it's gonna be another perfect day.
我跟你说过吧  你不能睡在这里
I thought I told you, you can't sleep in here!
完美
Perfect.
点点
Hey, Spot.
-小心身后  -好  过去吧
- Coming behind you. - All right, go ahead then.
过来  你这浑身生疮的杂种狗
Come here, you mangy mutt!
我受够了每天赶你了  流浪狗
I'm tired of kicking you out of here, street dog.
回去干活
Get back to work!
好  抓紧了
All right, hold on!
该去偷点早餐了
Time to steal some breakfast.
你好  狗狗  回头见
Hey, there, sonny boy. See you around.
你好啊
Hello!
啧  简直唾手可得
Pfft, this is too easy.
你好
Hello.
-你胆子真大  -女士
- How dare you! - Ma'am!
你妈的脸都给你丢光了
Your mother would be ashamed of you!
女士
Ma'am!
要不是这么饿我肯定会感到愧疚
I'd feel bad if I wasn't so hungry.
我猜猜  被装在盒子里遗弃在路边
Let me guess, left in a box by the side of the road?
这一套我都听烦了  走开
You know what? I've heard it before, so beat it.
-你们要自己去找午餐  -我饿了
- You gotta earn your lunch. - I hungry.
你的声音不可能这么萌
There is no way your voice is that cute.
-别装了  好好说  -求你了
- What's your real voice? - Please?
你本来就这声音
That's your voice?
好吧  算了  行
All right, you know what? Fine.
我不吃这一套  但我尊重你们的努力
Look, I'm not buying the hustle, but I respect the effort.
记住我这话  大概六个月后
But take it from me, in about six months,
等你们变声了  这招就不管用了
that voice is gonna drop and the bit's dead.
得来全不费功夫啊
That was too easy.
药店
不  我最喜欢的捕狗人
Oh, no. My favorite dog catcher.
这镇上又不是只有我一条狗
There are other dogs in this town, you know.
看这边
Hey! Over here!
佩吉和牛头在这边  想跟你谈谈
It's Peg and Bull. Wanna talk to ya.
流浪狗收容所
老天  只要我装作没看见  也许就...
Oh, man! Maybe if I just act like I don't see them...
别装作没看见我们似的
Don't act like you don't see us.
救命  我们被抓了
Help! We got caught!
警告
没有许可证的狗
要被立即抓进收容所
市政府指示
日安  先生  我只是来贴告示  无需紧张
Good day, sir. Just posting bills. No need for alarm.
我已把这附近的危险动物清理干净了
I already cleared this block of dangerous animals.
但我还在找一条狡猾的流浪狗
But I'm still looking for a cunning street dog.
-我能把这个贴在你窗户上吗  -不行
- May I hang this on your window? - No, you cannot.
-帮我一下又不花钱  -不行
- There's no charge for helping me. - No.
它有魔鬼般的眼睛  鲨鱼般的牙齿
He has demon eyes and teeth like a shark.
你说的还是狗吗
You still talking about a dog?
说吧  怎么回事
All right, what happened?
-我们打劫了肉铺  -又去了
- We robbed the butcher shop. - Again?
牛头吃了三公斤牛肉
Bull ate seven pounds of beef,
四块羊排  还有一整条烘肉卷
four lamb chops, and a whole meatloaf.
-我吐得天翻地覆  -没错
- I threw up everywhere. - Yeah.
我生命中最辉煌的一天
Best day of my life!
老天  跟你说过多少次了  肉铺只能单干
God, I keep telling ya the butcher's shop's a one-man-job.
如果你们不学会分头行动  总是会被抓到
You're always gonna get caught if you don't learn to split up!
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
我们宁愿被关在一起  也不愿独自在街头流浪
We'd rather be locked up together, than out on the streets alone.
独自  你说的是自由吧
Alone? Uh, I think you mean free?
瞧  你俩关在一起
See, while you're locked up together,
我自由自在  无牵无挂
I'm free to be myself, and I'm free to be by myself.
-是是是  知道了  -你天天挂在嘴上
- Yeah, yeah, we know. - Ya say it all the time.
既然你这么自由自在  那就把我们放出来吧
Since you feel so free, feel free to bust us outta here.
不不不  你们不明白
Oh, no, no, no. You guys don't understand.
我不能再惹这家伙了
I can't mess with this guy again.
但你喜欢把他耍得团团转
But ya love makin' him look like a fool.
抱歉  我帮不了你们了
I'm sorry, guys, you're on your own.
你可以的  把门砸了  砸门
You can do it. Just bust. Bust. Bust.
砸门  砸门  砸门
Bust. Bust. Bust. Bust.
好吧  我帮  别叫了
Okay! I'll do it. Stop yelling.
棒耶  他要帮我们了
Yeah! He's gonna do it.
-他要帮我们了  佩吉  -别叫  嘘  他过来了
- Yeah! He'll do it, Peg. - No... Shh! He's coming over.
我有点难受
I don't feel so good.
-他在做什么  -别问我  我什么也看不见
- What's he doin'? - Don't ask me. I can't see anything.
是什么
What is that?
瞧瞧看  送上门来了
Well, well, well, just the dog I was looking for.
你怎么了  病了
What are you, sick?
不  他病了  吐出来
Oh, no, he's sick. Just throw up.
再吃下去你就好了
You'll feel much better once you eat it.
我抓到你了
I got you.
他们绝对想不到我会抓到你
They never thought I'd get ya.
又耍我
Not again!
够了  我要放弃这种犯罪生活
That's it. I'm giving up the life of crime.
我们也可以回屠夫那里去
Or we can go back to the butcher.
说起来我又饿了
I could eat. Yeah.
回来
Come back here!
借过  美女  借过
Hey, excuse me! Hey! Hot stuff, coming through!
你俩是双胞胎吗
Are you two, uh, twins?
我是她丈夫  伙计
I'm her husband, pal.
-快让路  停下  -好吧  恭喜了
- Clear a path! Halt! - Yeah. Yeah, well, congratulations!
快回来
Hey, come back here!
抓住它
Grab him!
谁帮忙拦住它  快啊  肮脏的臭狗...
Somebody stop him! Come on! Dirty mangy...
菲尔  小心
Phil, watch out!
你一定得尝尝这个
You have got to try this.
还好吗
How's it going?
是啊
Yeah.
不是该带我去散步了吗
Isn't it time for my walk?
看看我买的这双靴子多美
Look at these cute booties I got.
真漂亮
So pretty!
我不知道你要来
I didn't know you were coming.
到时候将会有尖叫  嚎哭  呕吐
There's gonna be screaming, crying, vomiting.
然后  宝宝就出生了
And then, there's the baby.
来  我给你满上  好
Here let me top you off. Fair enough.
我们都得祝贺你  敬准爸爸
Congratulations is in order, to the father to be.
-敬吉姆  -大伙干杯
- To Jim! - Cheers. Everybody.
感觉怪怪的
That was weird.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you! - You're welcome.
不是拨浪鼓  别担心
It's not a rattle. Don't worry.
-真可爱  -你喜欢吗
- It's adorable. - You like it?
天啊  她肯定穿不下
Oh, my goodness. That is not gonna fit her.
我最爱的侄女呢
Where is my favorite niece?
-拿一下好吗  你拿着  -当然
- Could you just? Yes. There you go. - Oh. Sure.
她在哪  她在这里啊
Where is she? Oh, there she is!
-莎拉姑姑  你来了  -当然了
- Aunt Sarah! You made it! - Of course!
这是送给你的
This is for you.
-你不该这么客气的  -我知道
- You shouldn't have. - I know.
是的  是原版的锡釉彩陶
Yes, it's an original Majolica.
它能让这里蓬荜生辉
It's gonna do wonders for this room
我知道凭吉姆的工资肯定买不起  毕竟他只是个...
and I knew Jim couldn't afford one with the salary of a, uh...
-音乐家吗  -你说是就是吧  亲爱的
- Musician? - If you say so, dear.
-谢谢  -宝宝肯定会喜欢的
- Thank you. - I'm sure the baby will love it.
-这可是无价之宝  -下去  下去
- This is priceless! - Down, down!
不行  坏狗狗
No! Bad dog!
这狗该教训了
That dog needs to be trained.
它平时很乖的
She's, uh, normally really good.
你说的是猫吧
I think you're thinking of cats.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
这就停车了吗  你这算什么跑路司机啊
We're stopping? Ugh. Some getaway driver you are.
好吧  我在这下车了
All right, I'll hop out here.
势利山庄啊
Snob hill.
天  那家伙对我还真执着
Oh, my gosh! This guy's obsessed with me.
好吧  我得低调一阵子
All right, I gotta lay low for a while.
坏狗狗
"Bad dog"?
我做错什么了
What did I do wrong?
老信
Hey, Trusty!
Trusty?
怎么了
Yeah? Yes?
发生了一些很奇怪的事
Something strange is going on,
我真的需要跟朋友倾诉一下
and I really need to talk to a friend.
那些人都挤在屋子里
All these people are in the house,
有很多玩具  但都不是给我的
there's a bunch of toys, none of them are for me.
他们从今早到现在还没有给我梳毛
I haven't even been brushed since this morning.
我都快打结了
I'm getting tangly.
而且我的午后零食居然是凉的  凉的
And my afternoon snack was cold. Cold!
天  听起来真糟
Oh, boy. Sounds rough.
我都不记得达令上次给我揉肚子
And, I can't even remember the last time
是什么时候的事了
that Darling gave me a belly rub.
说到肚子  达令的肚子变得真的很大
Speaking of bellies, Darling's tummy is getting really big.
肯定是吃太多零食胀气了  我们都经历过
I'm pretty sure it's gas, too many treats. We've all been there.
而吉姆  我说不好  他看起来很正常
And Jim Dear, I don't know, he seems normal but...
可你知道吗  我总在他身上闻到恐惧的气味
You know what? I smell fear on him all the time.
所以我猜他并不那么正常
So, I guess that's not that normal.
-我不知道  -是啊  听起来真糟
- I don't know. - Yeah, that sounds bad.
你的声音
You sound...
你...你不是老信
Hey, you're... You're not Trusty.
-对  可你...  -我刚说的你都听到了
- Correct. But, you... - Did you just hear everything that I said?
-是的  -你的项圈呢
- Yes. - Where is your collar?
-说来话长  -老信呢
- Yeah, long story. - Where is Trusty?
老信  他肯定在哪里
Trusty, I'm sure, is somewhere.
-你在这里做什么  -老信
- What are you doing in there? - Trusty?
-快走开  -老信
- Get out of here! - Trusty?
我家主人就在里面  我要叫他们来
Hey, my people are inside, I'm goona warn them.
什么  不  别这样
What? No, no. Hey.
别叫人类过来  好吗
Let's not warn the people, okay?
我也想离开  可现在不行
Now, I would get out of here but I can't,
我不是来惹麻烦的
and I'm not here to make trouble,
我才是遇到麻烦的那个  你可以帮我
I'm the one in trouble and you could help me out here.
-我要叫了  -不  拜托  我可以解释
- I'm gonna bark. - No, please just... I can explain.
-稍等片刻  我过来  -来这里
- Just gimme a second. I'm comin' over. - Here?
你以为你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
-我要叫了  -不  拜托别叫
- Hey! I'm gonna bark. - No. Please, do not do that!
-我要叫了  -千万别
- I'm gonna bark. - Absolutely do not do that.
别  嘘  别叫了
Stop. Hey, hey! Shh! Stop it!
别指挥我该怎么做
Don't tell me what to do.
怎么回事
What?
等等  别叫了
Wait... Hang on!
好吧  你知道吗
All right. You know what?
我听到你刚才说的那些了  你没有反应过度
I heard what you said back there and you're not overreacting.
拜托  求你了
Come on. Please, please!
听着  如果你安静点
Look, if you keep it down,
我就告诉你关于那个宝宝的真相
I will tell you the truth about that baby!
那个什么
That... What?
糟糕
Oh, man!
没事吧  淑女
Everything all right, Lady?
是你的狗在叫吗
That your dog barking?
-什么  -是你的狗在叫吗
- What? - That your dog barking?
是的  它是我的狗
Yeah. She's mine.
还看到什么了吗
Seen anything else?
我在找这附近一个很危险的动物
I'm looking for a dangerous animal around here.
是有熊吗
Like a bear?
更糟  一条流浪狗
Worse, a stray dog.
灰色的公狗  有半米多长
Grey male, about two-foot four.
-浑身生疮  肮脏不堪  非常危险  -拜托  不要
- Mangy, dirty, dangerous. - Please, don't.
你是在朝流浪狗叫吗  淑女
You barking at a stray, Lady?
求你了
I'm begging you.
好吧
Fine.
看起来没什么事
Everything seems to be fine.
你确定吗  它浑身生疮  肮脏不堪
You sure now? He's mangy, and dirty...
-非常危险  -非常危险
- And dangerous? - Dangerous.
好吧
Yes, right.
说起来  我们这里最近
Actually, you know, we've been having
一直有点闹老鼠
a bit of a rat problem, recently.
老鼠
A rodent?
它会跑进院子里
He's been getting into the yard,
破坏我们的食物之类的
and spoiling our food, things like that.
领居们也遇到了
The neighbors too.
我不碰害兽  它们身上有病菌
I don't associate myself with vermin. They carry disease.
也对  好吧
Ah, right. Well...
那...谢谢了
Then, um... Then thank you.
谢你
For...
不管这算什么
Whatever this was.
尽职尽责
Commitment.
好吧
Okay.
天
Oh, my!
谢了  不能说是愉快的经历  再见
Thanks. Well, can't say it's been fun. Bye!
别急  你刚才说的是什么意思  关于宝宝
Not so fast. What did you mean back there, about the baby?
现在你想让我帮忙了
So now you want my help?
你想让我继续叫吗
Do you want me to bark again?
好吧  我该怎么说呢
Oh, fine. How can I put this?
你是你主人世界的中心  对吧
You're the center of your people's universe, right?
-可以这么说  -他们让你用浴盆  给你抹香波
- You could say that. - They shampoo you in the bathtub,
-让你睡在他们的床上  -你是说我们的床吗
- let you sleep in the bed? - You mean, our bed?
给你在这里建了个这么大的厕所
Build you this 40/40 bathroom right here?
恶心  我会在散步时解决
Gross. I have walks for that.
-好吧  那一切现在基本都结束了  -什么
- Well, that's basically all over now. - What?
你就要被取代了
You're about to be replaced.
-被取代  我  -对
- Replaced? Me? - Yeah.
我不这么认为  你可以走了
I don't think so. You can leave.
淑女  你还好吗
Lady! Are you okay?
-离她远点  杂种狗  -那是啥玩意
- Stay back, mongrel! - What is that?
我马上过去  我要报警了
I'll be right over. I'm callin' the cops!
你现在可以走了
I think you can be on your way now.
谢谢你的帮忙
Thanks for your help.
是你请我帮忙的
Whoa! You asked for my help.
听着  这话你可能不想听  但我了解人类
Now look, you may not wanna hear this, but I know people, okay?
人类并不忠诚
And people are not loyal,
你越快开始照顾你自己
and the sooner you start looking out for yourself,
我是说只想着你自己  就越好
and I mean, only yourself, the better.
这话也太消极了  而且并不是真的
Wow, that is incredibly depressing and also not true.
谢谢你什么也没帮上  再见
So, thanks for nothing. Bye.
淑女  你和你的朋友最好小心点
Lady, you and your friend better be careful.
我嗅到了闯入者的气息
I smell an intruder afoot.
就是他  老信
That's him, Trusty!
警察的工作就交给我吧
Leave the police work to me.
好怕怕  老信警官来了  救命啊  来得正好
Oh, no! It's Officer Trusty, help. Just in the nick of time.
-别得寸进尺  -围巾可别掉了  杀手
- Hey! Don't push it! - Keep your scarf on, killer.
好了两位  谢谢支援  不过他已经要走了
Okay, you two, thank you for the back-up but he was just leaving.
是吧  流浪狗
Weren't you, street dog?
流浪狗  我懂了
Street dog? Oh, I got it.
我会走的  但只是因为我想走就能走
I'll go, but only because I'm free to leave
而你们都被困在栅栏后面
while all of you are stuck behind your fences.
记住了  宝宝出生
Just remember, when the baby moves in,
狗狗就扔
the dog moves out.
对了  这个我偷走了
I'm stealing this by the way.
那是我让你偷走的
Hey, I let you steal that!
被宝宝取代  无稽之谈
Replaced by a baby? Makes no sense.
-不可能  -无稽
- No way. - None.
毕竟  宝宝能给他们拿拖鞋吗
I mean, can a baby fetch slippers?
-深表怀疑  -别傻了
- Doubtful. - Don't be daft.
会给他们捡报纸吗
Or pick up the paper.
-不可能  -可笑
- Not a chance. - Ridiculous.
宝宝能让吉姆和达令
Can a baby provide Jim and Darling
感到生命完整  找到人生意义吗
with the sense of wholeness and a reason to live?
-这个嘛  -呃
- Well... - Uh...
我就是这个意思
My point exactly.
医生  我只想说太感谢你了
Doc, actually just wanted to say, thank you so much.
我简直不敢相信  你看到她了吗
I just can't believe it. Did you see her?
我不敢相信她那么完美
I just can't believe how perfect she is.
你见过比她还漂亮的女婴吗
I mean, have you ever seen a more beautiful baby girl?
没有  我干接生这行已经38年了
No. In my 38 years of delivering babies,
你家宝宝是最漂亮的宝宝
your baby is the most beautiful baby.
-真的吗  -晚安
- Really? - Good night!
-我送你出去  -不了  谢谢
- I'll walk you out. - No, thank you.
达令  你听到了吗
Darling, did you hear that?
我还是不敢相信
I still can't believe it.
祝你好运
Good luck.
♪ 啦啦露  啦啦露 ♪
♪ La la lu, la la lu ♪
♪ 我的小小扫星人 ♪
♪ Oh, my little star sweeper ♪
♪ 我愿为你扫星尘 ♪
♪ I'll sweep the stardust for you ♪
淑女
♪ 啦啦露  啦啦露 ♪
♪ La la lu, la la lu ♪
♪ 毛茸茸的小小睡梦人 ♪
♪ Little soft fluffy sleeper ♪
♪ 送你一朵粉色的云 ♪
♪ Here comes a pink cloud for you ♪
♪ 啦啦露  啦啦露 ♪
♪ La la lu, la la lu ♪
♪ 漫游的小小天使 ♪
♪ Little wandering angel ♪
♪ 折起你的双翼 ♪
♪ Fold up your wings ♪
♪ 闭上眼睛 ♪
♪ Close your eyes ♪
♪ 啦啦露  啦啦露 ♪
♪ La la lu, la la lu ♪
♪ 愿爱成为你的守护者 ♪
♪ And may love be your keeper ♪
♪ 啦啦露  啦啦露  啦啦露 ♪
♪ La la lu, la la lu, la la lu ♪
淑女  现在不行  这是宝宝的房间
Lady, not now. This is the baby's room.
宝宝
Baby.
真乖  老信  要吃吗
That's a good boy, Trusty. Want some?
我一个  老信一个
One for me, one for Trusty...
怎么样  伙计
How's that, buddy?
英国全军总司令  没错  就是她
Commander of the entire British army, yes, she is!
乔克要进行什么冒险呢
What adventures is Jock going to get into?
开始了  一  二  三  拍
Here we go. And one, two, three... And!
就是这样  乔克
That was it, Jocky!
真是我的乖狗狗
That's my good girl.
来亲亲妈咪  谁是我的大明星啊
Give mommy kisses. Who's my big star?
我也爱你  我也爱你
I love you, too. I love you, too.
什么
What?
不好
Oh, no.
淑女  宝宝在睡觉
Lady! The baby is sleeping!
宝宝出生  狗狗就扔
When the baby moves in, the dog moves out.
来了
Coming.
莎拉姑姑  谢谢你...
Aunt Sarah. Thank you for...
-她在这儿呢  -当然了  别在意我
- There she is! - Yes, of course, don't mind me.
长得跟她妈妈一样  红扑扑的小脸
Looking just like her mommy. Positively glowing.
还有你  才一个月身材就恢复了
And you. Only a month and your figure's already returning.
-太棒了  -谢谢
- It's just lovely. - Thank you.
你还是没变
And you look the same.
莎拉姑姑  谢谢你在我们出门时照看淑女
Thank you, Aunt Sarah, for watching Lady while we're gone.
淑女
Lady?
照看狗吗  我以为我要照看小露露
Dog-sitting? I thought I'd be with little Lulu.
吉姆的姐姐坚持让我们带上露露
Well, Jim's sister, she was insistent that we bring her along.
是吗
Was she now?
非常感谢你的帮助
Thank you so much for your help.
如果我们能劳烦其他人
I mean, if we could've bothered anyone else,
相信我  我们会的
believe me, we would have.
好了
Right.
-再次感谢  -好的
- But thanks again. - Yeah.
-再见  -再见  淑女
- Bye. - Goodbye, Lady.
你要乖乖的哦
You be a good girl.
我还没能抱一抱她
I didn't even get to hold her.
快走了  亲爱的  拜
Come on, dear. Bye!
-拜拜  -拜
- Goodbye! - Bye!
你好  拜拜
Hello. Bye-bye.
你们会回来吗
Are you coming back?
-拜拜  -再见了
- Bye-bye! - Toodeloo.
照看狗  这不是在玩我吧
Dog-sitting. You've got to be kidding me.
我这打扮可不是为了狗
I'm not even dressed for this.
他们就那么把宝宝带走了
They just took the baby?
什么
What?
猫  好吧
Cats. Okay.
瞧瞧这地方
Look at this place.
-是啊  我们需要做些改变  -真遗憾
- Yeah, we'll need to make some changes. - What a shame.
我家有几条规矩  天啊
Okay, we have a few rules here. Oh, boy.
♪ 乖乖地原地坐下 ♪
♪ Now sit right there and take a seat ♪
♪ 我们来你肯定高兴 ♪
♪ I'm sure you're glad we came ♪
♪ 但我们要清理一番 ♪
♪ But we've got some cleaning up to do ♪
♪ 我们需要重新整理 ♪
♪ We'll need to rearrange ♪
好痒
That tickles.
♪ 这个家具我们来处理 ♪
♪ We'll take care of this furniture ♪
♪ 如果你没意见的话 ♪
♪ If to you it's all the same ♪
不要  我们不能这样做...
No, that... That's not something that we do...
♪ 但若你不喜欢我们的装修 ♪
♪ But if you don't like how we decorate ♪
♪ 太糟糕了  真遗憾 ♪
♪ Well, that's too bad, what a shame ♪
不  不要  拜托  那是易碎品  不要
No, no, don't. Please, those are fragile. Don't!
♪ 太糟糕了  真遗憾 ♪
♪ Well, that's too bad What a shame ♪
够了  住手
Okay. That's it!
♪ 我想我们可以重装椅面 ♪
♪ I think that we could reupholster here ♪
♪ 这个小塑像太过时 ♪
♪ This figurine is so last year ♪
淑女  安静
Lady! Quiet!
♪ 这些桌子需要重新装 ♪
♪ These tables need refurbishing ♪
♪ 窗帘需要换个新 ♪
♪ These curtains need a change ♪
♪ 但若你不喜欢我们的艺术品位 ♪
♪ But if you don't like our artistic flair ♪
♪ 太糟糕了  真遗憾 ♪
♪ Well, that's too bad, what a shame ♪
我要告状
I'm telling!
淑女  我说了安静
Lady! I said be quiet!
♪ 无话可说了吗 ♪
♪ Cat got your tongue? ♪
♪ 你为什么这么恼火 ♪
♪ Why are you so miffed ♪
♪ 我们让你家客厅更时髦 ♪
♪ We gave your living room a modern twist ♪
♪ 我们想要得到赞赏  不是批评 ♪
♪ And we gon' want some credit for this, not blame ♪
♪ 你疯了吗  真遗憾 ♪
♪ Are you mad? What a shame ♪
-那是我的  -所以呢
- That's mine. - Yes, and?
淑女
-这样好多了  -没错
- That's better. - Yeah.
这让房间更协调
It really holds the room together.
不不不
No, no, no.
摆花  不是吧
Flowers, really?
♪ 这里的色彩设计真疯狂[布谷鸟钟] ♪
♪ The color scheme in here is cuckoo ♪
♪ 我们是否犯了低级错误 ♪
♪ Did we make a boo-boo? ♪
♪ 是时候毁了这个钟 ♪
♪ It's time to break this thing ♪
♪ 一旦干完  我们就说再见 ♪
♪ As soon as we get done then we'll bid you auf Wiedersehen ♪
♪ 即使出岔子我们也早走了 ♪
♪ But if things go wrong then we'll be gone ♪
♪ 太糟糕了  真遗憾 ♪
♪ And that's too bad, what a shame ♪
♪ 我必须处理掉这个花瓶 ♪
♪ I gotta do somethin' about this vase ♪
从上面下来
Get down from there!
♪ 放这里有点突兀 ♪
♪ Yeah, it's just a tiny bit out of place ♪
♪ 别摔你脸上  噢耶 ♪
♪ Don't let it fall on your face oh, yeah ♪
不不不  不要
No, no, no. Don't.
不要  不要
Oh, no. Oh, no.
我的宝贝们
My babies.
淑女
Lady!
你好
Howdy?
借过  你好
Excuse me. Hello.
-下午好  女士  -下午好
- Good afternoon, ma'am! - Good afternoon.
欢迎  别介意鹦哥  我能帮你什么
Welcome. Don't mind Polly. May I help you?
希望你可以
I hope so.
这个可爱的小天使是谁
Who is this precious little angel?
它叫淑女  但我认为这名字不适合它
Her name is Lady, though I daresay the name doesn't suit her.
不适合吗
No?
我需要让它别再恐吓我们
I need to keep her from terrorizing us any longer.
好的  训练背带怎么样
Yes. Well, how about a training harness?
汪汪
Woof, woof.
它不服训教
She can't be trained.
那么...咀嚼玩具怎么样
Well, then how about... a chew toy?
你觉得它该受到奖励吗
You think she needs to be rewarded?
那个呢
What about that?
不不  你确定有这必要吗
No, no, no. Are you sure that's absolutely necessary?
是的
Yes.
马上来
Right away.
那好吧  过来  小可爱
All right, then. Here, sweet thing.
我知道
I know.
乖乖的
Be a good girl.
-女士  它不想要  -我想
- Ma'am, she doesn't want it. - I want it!
-我知道  很抱歉  -按住它
- I know. I'm so sorry. - Well, hold her!
-我正...  -你能按住...
- I'm doing my... - Can you hold...
-抓住它  -我的鸟  抱歉
- Get her! - My birds! Sorry!
这里卖鸟吗
Do you sell birds?
好了各位  开始了
All right, everybody, here we go!
当心
Watch out there!
看路
Watch out!
疯了  真是疯了
This is crazy. This is crazy.
当然了  死胡同
Of course. A dead end.
这小巷是我的
I own this alley.
至少你不住这里
At least you don't live here.
我也住这里
I also live here.
非常抱歉
I am so sorry.
再一看  这里很漂亮
Looking at it again, it's a beautiful space.
离我的东西远点  小偷
Back away from my stuff, thief.
小偷  我从来没有偷过东西  谢谢
Thief? I have never stolen a thing in my life, thank you.
我也不准备从偷这垃圾开始
And I'm not gonna start with this garbage.
那是我的食物
That's my food.
食物  好吧
Food? Okay...
你想愚弄我吗
You trying to make a fool out of me?
那可不容易做到
'Cause that's not easy to do.
好吧  我这就走了
Okay. You know what, I'm just gonna go.
我发现我不该来这里
I realize I've been an imposition.
不  你哪也别想去
No, you're not going anywhere.
-住手  -什么
- Stop! - What?
快停下
Just stop.
好极了  流浪汉来了
Great. It's the tramp.
不要轻举妄动
Don't make any sudden moves.
你面对的是个杀手
You're dealing with a killer here.
是呵  哈巴狗  杀手
Yeah, lap dog. A killer.
冷静  我不是说你
Stay calm. I'm not talking about you.
-我在说她  -什么
- I'm talking about her. - What?
-什么  -谁
- What? - Who?
-别被她软趴趴的耳朵骗了  -什么
- Don't let those floppy ears fool you, man. - What?
拜托  难道你不好奇她为什么戴着口套吗
Come on. Aren't you wondering why she's wearing a muzzle?
为什么这么一条讨厌的小狗会来你家
Why such a tiny, annoying, little dog would come into your home?
-讨厌  -是啊  我确实好奇
- Annoying? - Yeah. You know, I was wondering about that.
这是条狂犬
This dog is rabid.
她是兔子吗[音似]She's a rabbit?
-你知道狂犬是什么意思吧  -知道
- You know what rabid means, right? - Yeah?
就是狂犬病  知道吗
Like, rabies, you know?
行为危险  有传染性  可怕
Like, when you act dangerous and contagious and scary.
好像要杀生
Like, you're gonna kill someone.
我有狂犬病
I have rabies!
-我行为危险  -我的老天
- I am acting dangerous! - Oh, my goodness!
-冷静  冷静  -还有传染性
- Easy, easy. - And contagious!
有时候表现得没这么夸张
And sometimes, it's even a little more subtle than that.
-狂犬病  狂犬病  -有时候就这么夸张
- Rabies! Rabies! Rabies! - And sometimes, it's not.
她病得不轻  是不是
She's got it bad, doesn't she?
当心  她朝你的存货去了
Look out! She's headed for your stash!
-我有吗  -是的
- I am? - Yes, you are.
没错  我要去  我要到处传播狂犬病
Right! Yes, I am! I'm getting rabies everywhere!
连香肠都不放过吗
Even the sausages?
对
Oh, yeah!
-什么  -对  尤其是香肠
- What? - Yes, especially on the sausages.
-现在香肠也染上狂犬病了  -我们怎么办
- These are rabies sausages now. - What do we do?
快跑  自救
Quick, run! Save yourself!
我的香肠怎么办
What about my sausages?
快走  别管它了
Just go! Just leave it!
-她来了  -等等  停  她追上我了
- Here she comes! - Wait, stop! I think she's got me!
抱歉  你自救吧
Sorry, you're on your own.
真过瘾
I feel alive.
狂犬病
Rabies!
等等  我好想记得你管我叫流浪狗
Wait, I seem to remember you calling me a street dog,
但你现在也在街头
but here you are out on the streets.
奇怪  我猜猜  宝宝出生  狗狗就扔
Strange. Let me guess, baby moves in, dog moves out?
不  根本不是那样
No, not at all!
这事...不是你想的那样
This here... this is not what it looks like.
对了  救你一命这事  不用客气
You're welcome for saving your life, by the way.
作为交换  我给了你一顿免费午餐
And in exchange, I got you a free meal.
所以我们扯平了
So, I think we're even.
这是我听过最疯狂的"谢谢"
That's the craziest "thank you" I've ever gotten.
也许你确实有狂犬病
Maybe you do have rabies.
行  真好笑  既然我帮你吃到了那垃圾
Great. Hilarious. Okay, well, seeing as I'm the reason
你能帮我摘掉脸上这东西吗
that you got that garbage, how about you help me get this thing off my face.
好吧  我尽力而为
Fine. I'll see what I can do.
我有一个能帮上忙的朋友
I think I got a friend who can help.
他挺冷硬的  有点像你
Now, he's a little stiff. Kinda reminds me of you.
我已经开始后悔了
I'm already regretting this.
这就是你朋友
This is your friend?
拜托你别犯傻  这才是我朋友
Please. Don't be ridiculous. This is my friend.
-当然是这位了  -来
- Of course it is. - Come on.
你只要把钢圈挂到它牙上就行
You just need to hook that wire onto his teeth.
你准备让它咬下来吗
Is your plan for him to bite it off?
你能照办吗
Would you just do it?
像这样
Like this?
好像没什么用
This doesn't feel like progress.
你到底要不要我帮你
Do you want me to help you or not?
你往后挪一点  固定住这东西
Just lean back so this thing doesn't move...
你动作快点
I guess. Just make it quick.
然后我把这玩意咬松  这是什么
while I work this thing loose. What is this?
是我耳朵  拜托
That's my ear, please.
什么  你能别乱动吗
What? Could you stop moving so much?
你踩到我爪子了
You stepped on my paw.
抱歉  我不是故意的
Oh, sorry! I didn't mean to.
这一点也不尴尬
This is not awkward at all.
我数三声  我们一起
On my count, we're both gonna need to pull
使最大的力气往后拽  准备好了吗
as hard as we can. You ready?
-好了  -一
- Yeah. - One...
-二  -我来数
- Two. - My count.
-好  -二  三
- Okay. - Two... Three.
告诉你能行的
Told you it would work.
对  谢谢你帮我忙
Yep. Well, thanks for your help.
谢谢你  我是说
Thank you. I mean, yeah,
-不客气  -也谢谢你
- you're welcome. - Yeah... thank you, too.
祝你在家玩得开心  宝贝
Have fun at home, baby.
我是说  和宝宝玩得开心
I mean, with the baby.
什么
What?
没啥  当我没说
No, uh... never mind.
该告别了
Well, this is goodbye, I think.
-对  -再见
- Yep. - Bye.
再见
Bye.
你...你好像迷路了
You, um... you look lost.
舒尔茨帽店
新潮女帽  应有尽有
我完全能够
I think I am capable of
自己找到回家的路  非常感谢
finding my own way home, thank you very much.
行
Oh, okay.
我大概不用告诉你走错了路
I guess I won't bother telling you that's the, uh, wrong way.
你要回家的话  那路就走错了
I mean, if you're going home, that would be the wrong way.
我知道  我只是想看看那边的情况
No, I know. I just wanted to see what was over there.
-现在我才要回家  -行
- Now, I'm going home. - Okay.
那边的路也不对
That's also the completely wrong way.
好吧  我迷路了
Okay, yes, I am lost.
你是准备站在那笑话我
So, you just gonna stand there
承包晚宴及甜点
还是要帮我忙
and mock me or are you gonna help me out?
只能二选一吗  因为理想情况下...
Is that an either or question? Because ideally...
你指个方向  我自己走  行吗
Just point. I'll be on my way, okay?
是那边  听好了  这里不是后院
It's that way. Now, listen, this isn't a backyard.
这里有这里的规矩  第一  眼观六路
There are rules. Lesson one. Always look both ways.
-跟上  -第二
- Catch up! - Lesson two.
车很重  撞上来很疼
Cars are heavy and they hurt!
你一条近路也不知道吗
Don't you know any shortcuts?
我们走的是观景路线
We're taking the scenic route.
希望最终能走回家
I would like to get home eventually.
你为什么想回家
Why do you even want to go home?
我告诉你了
I told you.
这事情只是个误会
This is just one big misunderstanding.
吉姆和达令现在肯定担心坏了
Jim Dear and Darling must be worried sick about me by now.
当然
Yeah, no, sure.
你那表情什么意思
What is that look?
我不想说难听话
Look, I hate to break it to you,
就是我没怎么看见"寻狗启事"的广告
I'm just not seeing a lot of "Lost dog" posters up...
你可能认为你很了解人类
You may think that you know people,
但是你不了解我的主人  好吗
but you don't know my people, okay?
他们绝对不会让我流落街头
They would never let me wind up on the streets.
不会故意这样
Not on purpose.
好吧  有道理
Okay, fair enough.
但你现在正在街上游荡  你没戴项圈
But you're walking around on the street. You have no collar.
没人牵引  你闻起来有点臭
You are off leash. You smell a tweensy bit like trash.
-真没礼貌  -也就是说  对那个捕狗人而言
- Rude. - Which means, to that dog catcher...
我在找一只流浪狗
I'm looking for a street dog.
外表非常邋遢  行动莫测
Really scruffy face. Unpredictable.
你就是流浪狗
You're a street dog,
所以我们才要走观景路线
so that's why we're sticking to the scenic route.
来  你说不定能找点乐子呢
Come on. You might even have fun.
流浪狗收容所
垂耳吗
Floppy ears?
-就是它  -我知道那狗
- That's the one. - Yeah, I know that dog.
-那是条恶狗  -对
- That dog's a menace. - Yes.
就睡在我的火车场
Sleeps in my train yard.
-带路  -来
- Show me. - Come on.
快点  我们得过河
Come on! We gotta get across the river.
坐那个
On that?
你没坐过船吗
Have you never been on a boat before?
我都没见过船  我们要怎么上船
I've never seen a boat before. How are we supposed to get on?
来  跟着我
Come on, follow me!
从这里  稍微一跳就行
Here. Just a quick little jump.
没门
No way.
拜托  很容易的  我跳给你看
Oh, come on, it's easy. I'll show you.
非常安全  当心水渍
Yeah, it's totally safe. Just watch out the wet spot, right?
有人在这里洒了点东西
There's someone spilled something.
是啊  我不跳
Yeah. I'm not gonna do that.
拜托  你会游泳  对吧
Come on! You know how to swim, right?
欢迎上船
Welcome aboard.
-你好  -你好  请出示船票
- How do you do? - Hello, ticket please?
-谢谢  -旅途愉快
- Thank you. - Enjoy.
下午好  请出示船票  你真可爱  对吗
Oh, good afternoon, ticket please. Well, aren't you just lovely?
耳朵尤其漂亮
And such gorgeous ears.
全体上船
All aboard!
-再见  -再见  一路顺风
- Goodbye! - Bye now! Have a nice trip!
干得不错  也许我低估你了
Not bad. Maybe I was wrong about you.
对  下次你冒不必要的生命危险前
Yeah, maybe next time you should ask me if I have any ideas
也许可以问问我的主意
before you risk your life unnecessarily.
你是说你不希望我死吗
Was this your way of saying that you don't want me to die?
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
-所以你希望我去死  -我也没那么说
- So now you want me to die? - And I didn't say that either.
-我才不信呢  小鬼  -我叫淑女
- Not buyin' it, kid. - It's Lady.
很高兴认识你  淑女
Nice to meet ya, Lady.
我也很高兴认识你...
Nice to meet you, too...
我都没问过你的名字  你叫什么
I never asked you your name. What's your name?
我有好多名字
I get called a lot of things.
包括伙计  狗狗  点点  布奇  滚
You know, I get Buddy or Pooch or Spot or Butch or Scram
或者  别翻垃圾
or Hey, get out of the trash.
要名字干嘛呢  我想做谁就做谁
Who needs a name, you know? I'm free to be whoever I wanna be.
自由自在  无牵无挂
Free to be myself and free to be by myself.
以天为庐  以地为塌  纵横四海  四海为家
Sky's my roof. Walk wherever I wanna walk.
走自己想走的步伐
I walk however I wanna walk.
你真疯狂
You're crazy.
这才哪到哪
You don't know the half of it.
-你想听点好听的吗  -好啊
- Hey, you wanna hear something great? - Sure!
他们真棒
They're amazing.
是吧  歌手更出色  听好了
Oh, yeah? Well, the singer's even better. Listen to this.
-顺便一说  自学的  -不
- Self-taught, by the way. - No.
我承认我技法可能不太娴熟
I admit I'm not the best technical singer.
但有时候音乐不在于音阶和音调
But sometimes it's not really about pitch or tone.
-而在于  -音量
- Sometimes it's just about... - Volume?
音量  音量显然很重要
Volume. Volume helps. Obviously.
-当然  -因为要让人家听到嘛
- Sure. - 'Cause you want people to hear you.
音量你没问题
Well, you have that part down.
-你也就音量没问题  -什么  大胆
- That's about all you have down. - What? How dare you?
你很努力了
It's an A for effort, I think...
你看  当一条流浪狗也没什么不好
See? Being a street dog isn't so bad at all.
能看到另一种风景
And it comes with a view.
好了  你可以停下了
Okay, you can stop now.
这世界这么大  有很多事可做
See, there's plenty to do out here in this big, old world.
的确如此
Yeah. I'll bet there is.
那公园真美
That park is pretty.
那公园埋了很多骨头
There's a lot of bones buried in that park.
死狗吗
Dogs died?
不  我们原来在那里藏吃剩的骨头
No, that's just where we used to bury all our bones.
你左边是这城里最早的消防栓
And on your left is the oldest fire hydrant in the city.
-也算是个地标了  -为什么
- Kind of a landmark around here. - Why is that?
不是吧  那是个消防栓啊
Seriously? It's a fire hydrant.
-对哦  真恶心  -狗  消防栓
- Oh, right. Gross. - Dogs, fire hydrant.
桥这边
And just beyond this bridge
我曾经在这里和一只臭鼬起过冲突
here is where I had a run-in with a skunk.
你闻到了吗
Do you smell that?
不  那是好多年前了  我当时还是条小狗
No, no, no. This was years ago. I was, like, a puppy. It was...
不不不
No, no, no, no.
这是什么
What is all this?
这里吗  这是城里我最喜欢的地方
This? This is, like, my favorite part of town.
是美食街
It's Restaurant Row.
面馆
美食街
Restaurant Row?
对  这里有法国剩饭
Yeah, they got French scraps,
中国剩饭  肉和土豆剩饭
Chinese scraps, meat and potato scraps.
-什么都有  -他们就直接给你吗
- They got it all. - And they just give it to you?
不是谁都给的  但是我例外
No, not just anyone. But to me, yes.
行  我们试试
Okay. Well, let's give it a try.
不是要送你回家吗
Don't we have to get you home?
对  回家
Yeah. Home.
你还好吗
You okay?
我...
I, uh...
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道我还有没有家
I'm not so sure I still have a home to get back to.
我想...肯定没事的
Hey, I'm... I'm sure it'll be okay.
不  你是对的
No, you were right.
宝宝出生  狗狗就扔
Baby moves in and the dog moves out.
事情和你预料的一样
It happened just the way that you said it would.
你大概觉得我就想听你这句话  但是
I know you probably think that's what I wanted to hear, but it...
不是的
It wasn't.
这样吧
You know what?
我们去找点吃的
Let's get something to eat.
我知道一个好地方
And I think I know just the place.
托尼餐馆
托尼餐馆  镇里我最喜欢的地方
Tony's. My favorite place in town.
闻起来真香  我们直接走进去吗
It smells amazing. Do we just walk right in?
其实我有自己的私人入口  跟我来
Actually I kinda use my own private entrance. Follow me.
等等我
Wait up.
我太饿了  能吃下一只鞋
I am so hungry I could eat a shoe.
我吃过  一般般吧
Done it before. Overrated.
你躲着别出来  晚餐我请
Okay, you stay hidden. Dinner's on me.
布奇  抱歉朋友  来得不是时候
Hey, Butch. I'm sorry, my friend. Bad timing.
今晚人满为患
It's a full house in there, you know?
这是哪位
Who is this?
你好  亲爱的  晚上好
Hola, mi amor. Buenas noches.
好吧  我去想想办法  好吗
Okay, let me see what I can do for you, okay?
乔  客人等着用餐呢
Joe? We got tables waiting.
好的  抱歉老板
Yes. Sorry, boss.
-我们都要忙死了  -我知道  你以为我不知道吗
- We're dying in there. - I know, I know! You think I don't know?
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你怎么不早说呢
Why didn't you say so?
你根本配不上它  布奇
She's way too good for you, Butch.
它是个可卡犬姑娘  是吗
She's a Cockerel Spanish girl, huh?
-乔  -我在
- Joe? - Yes?
-乔  听着  -早想到了
- Joe, listen, I... - Uh, way ahead of you.
骨头  你什么毛病
Bones! What's the matter with you?
今晚  布奇要享受最棒的晚餐
Tonight, Butch gets the best in the house.
我喜欢  最棒的晚餐
I love it, best in the house.
-来吧  我们能做到  -稍等一下
- Come on, we can do this. Go on. - One moment, please.
怎么回事
What's happening?
你问我吗
You're asking me?
-快点  -好
- Come on! - Okay.
快点  快点
Hurry up, hurry up.
我该做什么...
What do I do... What do I...
去拿蜡烛  面包棒
Get a candle. Bread sticks.
拿来了
I got it.
好了
All right.
-你能把蜡烛点上吗  -好的
- Can you light the candle? - Yes.
点蜡烛
Light the candle.
我正要点  我只有两只手
I'm going. I only have two hands.
店里最好的位置  你们可以落座了
The best table in the house. And now, your table is ready.
相信我
Take it from me,
最好点托尼的特色菜
you'll want Tony's speciale.
乔  布奇说他想要两份特色意大利面
Joe, Butch says he wants two spaghetti special.
多加肉丸
And heavy on the meatballs.
托尼  你是不是傻  狗不会说话
Are you silly, Tony? Dogs don't talk. Yeah?
但它跟我说话了
Well, he's talkin' to me.
-两份特色意大利面马上就来  -快点
- Two specials coming right up. - Hurry.
很抱歉  我马上去
I'm so sorry. Yeah I'm going.
街头生活是吗
Street life, huh?
是啊  除非有桌子  桌布
Yeah. You know, I won't even eat unless
蜡烛  菜单  否则我拒绝进餐
I have a table, and a table cloth, and a candle, and a menu.
我瞎说的  这都是因为有你
No. This is because you're here.
快来  快来
Come on. Come on.
给我们的狗狗  布奇  和它的新女朋友
For our boy, Butch, and his nice new lady friend.
-是的  -走吧  走吧
- Yes. - Come on. Come on.
-好的  -走吧
- Okay. - Come on.
祝你们好胃口
Buon appetito.
他们说特色菜卖完了
They told me they were out of the special.
天呐  我还以为他们俩要坐下来和我们一起吃呢
God, I thought those two were gonna sit down and join us.
别担心  他们不会打扰我们了
Don't worry. They won't bother us...
他们回来了
And they're back.
♪ 就是这个夜晚 ♪
♪ Oh, this is the night ♪
♪ 这个美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ It's a beautiful night ♪
♪ 用意大利语说就是 ♪
♪ And we call it ♪
♪ 美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ Bella notte ♪
♪ 看看夜空 ♪
♪ Look at the skies ♪
♪ 眼睛里有星星 ♪
♪ They have stars in their eyes ♪
♪ 在这美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ On this lovely bella notte ♪
♪ 与你的爱人肩并肩 ♪
♪ Side by side With your loved one ♪
♪ 今晚你会发现魔法 ♪
♪ You'll find enchantment here ♪
♪ 黑夜将编织它的魔咒 ♪
♪ The night will weave its magic spell ♪
♪ 当你所爱的人就在身旁 ♪
♪ When the one you love is near ♪
♪ 因为 ♪
♪ For ♪
♪ 就是这个夜晚 ♪
♪ This is the night ♪
♪ 天空夜色正美 ♪
♪ And the heavens are right ♪
♪ 在这美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ On this lovely bella notte ♪
♪ 就是这个夜晚 ♪
♪ This is the night ♪
♪ 这个美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ It's a beautiful night ♪
♪ 用意大利语说就是 ♪
♪ And we call it ♪
♪ 美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ Bella notte ♪
♪ 看看夜空 ♪
♪ Look at the skies ♪
♪ 眼睛里有星星 ♪
♪ They have stars in their eyes ♪
♪ 在这美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ On this lovely Bella notte ♪
♪ 与你的爱人肩并肩 ♪
♪ Side by side with your loved one ♪
♪ 今晚你会发现魔法 ♪
♪ You'll find enchantment here ♪
♪ 黑夜将编织它的魔咒 ♪
♪ The night will weave its magic spell ♪
♪ 当你所爱的人就在身旁 ♪
♪ When the one you love is near ♪
♪ 就是这个夜晚 ♪
♪ This is the night ♪
来  我带你看个东西
Come on, I wanna show you something.
♪ 天空夜色正美 ♪
♪ And the heavens are right ♪
♪ 在这美丽的夜晚 ♪
♪ On this lovely bella notte ♪
淑女  这是世界
Lady, the world.
世界  这是淑女
World, Lady.
我觉得你们俩会相处得很愉快
I think you two are gonna get along just great.
我睡在那边的火车场里
I sleep over there in the train yard
有时候我会来这里看风景
so, you know, sometimes I come up here just for the view.
白天肯定看得更清楚  不过
'Course you see more in the daylight but, you know,
野外的黑夜和星空有独特的魅力
there's something about the night, outside, under the stars.
我在院子里看过
I've seen them from the yard before,
但这...完全不同
but this is... This is something else.
你来试试
Now you try.
我不知道我会不会
I don't know if I can.
你当然会
Of course you can.
我以前从没嚎叫过
I've never howled before.
什么
What?
好吗  你只要挖掘内心
Okay, look, you just gotta reach down deep,
找到你内心深处的狼
and you gotta find that inner wolf inside you.
来吧
Go ahead.
让我准备一下  可能得用力挖掘
Okay, give me a minute. It might be buried deep.
太...太棒了
That was... That was great.
太棒了  你是真的想嚎叫
That was great. Was that a real attempt,
还是只是在热身
or were you just kinda warming up?
别这样  我以前从没试过
Hey! Come on, I've never done this before.
不像狂犬病那样自然而然就会了
Not coming to me as naturally as rabies did.
再让我试一次
Let me try again.
就是这样  感觉好吗
There you go! Did that feel good?
-感觉挺好的  -是啊
- That felt pretty good. - Yeah.
我觉得我们只需要改善你的...
I think we just need to work on your...
我的音量  你是想说这个吗
My volume? Is that what you were gonna say?
没错
Exactly.
我从没在这么高的地方看过这个镇子
I've never seen the town from this high up.
不知我能不能看到我的...
I wonder if I can see my...
我的房子
My house.
也没那么糟
It's not so bad.
瞧瞧你  你在这里  对着月亮嚎叫
Look at you now. You're up here, you're howling at the moon!
昨天  你所有的经历都是在栅栏后面
Yesterday, the only experiences you had were from behind a fence.
我知道  我知道
Yeah, I know! I know.
但是栅栏后面有很多东西
But there was a lot behind that fence.
知道吗
You know?
我的生活充满了爱和意义
My life was full of love and meaning.
我们是特别的存在
I was a part of something special.
我们是一家人
We were a family.
不管我们怎么嚎叫
It doesn't matter how much howling I do,
离开他们我都感到很难过
I feel bad about leaving them.
你不必担心离开他们
You don't have to worry about leaving them.
他们已经离开你了  我知道这有多伤心
They already left you. I mean, look, I know how much it hurts...
怎么可能  你怎么知道
No, how? How would you know?
我就是知道
I just do.
你确实知道
You do know.
你曾经有过家  是吗
You did have a home, didn't you?
是的
Yeah.
我有过
I did.
我有过家
I had a home.
我有过家人
I had a family.
我拥有过一切
Oh, I had it all.
他们爱我
They loved me.
我爱他们
And I loved them.
然后有一天  一切都变了
And then one day it all changed.
我在原地等了一天
I waited in that spot all day...
一夜
And all night.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我
I...
我不知道
I didn't know.
算了吧
Forget it.
每条狗都得长教训  对吧
Every dog's gotta learn someday, right?
人类就是不懂忠诚
People just don't do loyalty.
不像我们这些狗
Not like us dogs.
而且如果我还和他们在一起  就不会遇见你了
And if I were still with 'em, I wouldn't have met you.
我们也不会共度这么美好的一天
And we wouldn't have had this amazing day.
一夜
And night.
每一天都可以是一场冒险
Every day could be an adventure.
你和我  没人牵引没有栅栏
You and me, no leashes or fences...
不对任何人忠诚
No loyalty to anyone.
它一定就在这里
He's gotta be around here somewhere.
我找到你了
I found you!
-他找到我了  -什么
- He found me! - What?
我们得逃跑了  快跑
Run! We gotta run. Right now!
回来
Hey, get back here!
这次你逃不掉了  这次不行
You're not getting away this time! Not this time!
快  从这里走
Come on! Through here!
我们得分头跑  快点  去那边
We need to split up. Quick. Go that way.
什么  不  这太疯狂了  我们得待在一起
What? No, that's crazy. We have to stay together!
反正他在追我  我们最好单独行动
He's after me anyway. We're better off alone.
相信我  你错了
Trust me! You are wrong about this.
快跑
Run!
-你看到什么了吗  -还没有
- You see anything? - Not yet.
我们分头行动  把它赶出来  准备好
Let's split up. We're gonna flush him out. Be ready.
我会的
I will be.
过来  狗狗
Here, boy.
现在只剩你一个了  流浪狗
You're all alone now, street dog.
快出来吧
Come on out.
你不累吗
Aren't you tired?
赶紧的  我要关门了
Wrap it up. I'm closing shop.
-马上就好  -我们出去吧
- I'm almost done. - Let's get out.
-走吧  -我们走
- Come on. - Let's go.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
把门关上
Shut the door!
你给我站住
Don't run away from me.
站住
Stop!
它往你那边跑了
He's heading your way.
我没看见它
I don't see him.
过来  狗狗
Here, boy.
快出来吧
Come on out.
见鬼
Dang it.
就现在
Now!
我堵住它了
I got him.
别让它溜了
Don't let him get by.
绝不可能
Not a chance.
就这样  慢慢来
That's it, nice and easy.
淑女
Lady!
你干什么
Hey, hey, hey! What're you doing?
淑女  我们走
Lady, let's go!
抓住它
Get her!
快跑
Run for it!
太不可思议了  我们成功了
That was incredible! We made it!
淑女
Lady?
别哼唧了
Quit your whining.
淑女
Lady!
淑女  我这就...
Lady, I'm gonna...
我...
I...
我很抱歉  淑女
I'm so sorry, Lady.
流浪狗收容所
小鬼  你迷路了吗
You lost, kid?
她看起来很害怕
She looks scared.
别让他们吓到你  亲爱的
Don't let 'em scare you, honey.
在这里我们都是朋友
We're all friends in here.
阿科  你就这么对待客人吗
Arko, is that how you treat our guest?
你知道不能这样
You know better than that.
第一次来吗  亲爱的  这里可不常见家养狗
First time, love? Don't get many family dogs in here.
而且闻起来她好像洗过澡
Smells like she's had a bath, too.
我都不记得我上次洗澡是什么时候了
I can't remember the last time I had a bath.
这里是收容所  对吧
This is the pound, isn't it?
亲爱的  你不习惯来这种地方吧
Not used to digs like these, are ya, honey?
一月洗的  我想起来了
January! Just remembered.
别担心  这里有两种类型的狗
Don't worry. Here they've got two types of dogs.
可收养的  也就是你
Adoptable, which is you,
以及我们这些
and the rest of us.
为什么你们不可收养
Why aren't you adoptable?
宝贝  我们是流浪狗
Baby, we're street dogs.
我们没人要
We're strays.
我们中有些是罪犯
Some of us are criminals.
那是传闻
Allegedly.
流浪狗收容所
你们听啊  船回来了
You guys, listen. The boat's back.
你怎么流落到这里的
How did you end up here anyway?
我和一个朋友遇上麻烦  然后分开了
Well, a friend and I ran into trouble and got split up.
等等  你刚才说朋友
Hang on. Did you say friend?
是"真正的"朋友  还是"所谓的"朋友
Like a "friend" friend? Or a "friend"?
我回去帮他  但是我...
Well, I went back to help him, but I... I...
看来他不能帮我
I guess he couldn't help me.
不能  还是不愿
Couldn't or wouldn't?
你这个朋友有名字吗
Does this friend have a name?
他说他有很多名字
He said he had a lot of names.
老天  让我猜猜  布奇  点点
Oh, boy! Let me guess. Butch? Spot?
或者  别翻垃圾
Or, Hey, get out the trash?
你们一定要分开吗
Did you have to split up?
还是他说你最好单独行动
Or did he just say you're better off alone?
等等  你怎么知道
Wait. How did you know that?
因为我们认识他
'Cause the guy we know...
他是个独行侠
He's a lone wolf!
他只演独角戏
He's a solo act!
♪ 他是个流浪汉  但我们爱他 ♪
♪ He's a tramp but we love him ♪
♪ 每天都有新花招 ♪
♪ Pulls a new scam every day ♪
♪ 他是个流浪汉 ♪
♪ He's a tramp ♪
♪ 我们喜爱他 ♪
♪ We adore him ♪
♪ 我们知道他会一直这样下去 ♪
♪ And we know he'll always stay that way ♪
♪ 他是个流浪汉 ♪
♪ He's a tramp ♪
♪ 他很有魅力 ♪
♪ He's a charmer ♪
♪ 他狡猾多端  他机警敏锐 ♪
♪ He's a sly one and he's a ball ♪
♪ 他是个流浪汉  我们爱他 ♪
♪ He's a tramp and we love him ♪
♪ 不过别指望他对你唯命是从 ♪
♪ Oh, just don't expect him at your beck and call ♪
♪ 你永远不知道他什么时候会出现 ♪
♪ Listen, you can never tell when he'll show up ♪
♪ 他少不了给你添麻烦 ♪
♪ He gives you plenty of trouble ♪
♪ 他只是一条没出息的小狗 ♪
♪ I guess he's just a no 'count pup ♪
♪ 一出事就会立刻抛弃你 ♪
♪ Who will ditch you on the double ♪
♪ 他是个流浪汉 ♪
♪ He's a tramp ♪
♪ 他是个独行侠 ♪
♪ He's a loner ♪
♪ 没什么好说的了 ♪
♪ And there's nothing more to say ♪
♪ 如果他是个流浪汉 ♪
♪ If he's a tramp ♪
♪ 那谁还需要他呢 ♪
♪ Then who needs him? ♪
♪ 我们知道他会一直这样下去 ♪
♪ Oh, we know he'll always stay that way ♪
♪ 他从不改变 ♪
♪ He never changes ♪
听我们的  亲爱的
Listen, darling.
♪ 我们知道他会一直这样下去 ♪
♪ We know he'll always stay that way ♪
♪ 我们是想帮你 ♪
♪ We're trying to help ya ♪
♪ 我们知道他会一直这样下去 ♪
♪ We know he'll always stay that way! ♪
一个流浪汉
A tramp.
来吧  该走了
Come on. It's time to go.
是疯子
It's Nutsy.
他要回家了吗
Is he going home?
他们要带他去哪
Where're they taking him?
穿过那扇单行门
Through the one-way door.
流浪狗收容所
来吧  该走了
Come on, it's time to go.
淑女  你没事吧
Lady! Are you okay?
淑女  我们很抱歉
Lady, we're so sorry.
见到你我太高兴了
I'm so glad to see you.
你一定吓坏了
You must've been terrified!
狗不应该在街头游荡
The street's no place for a dog.
别担心  我们要回家了
Don't worry. We're going home.
我们带你回家吧
Let's get you home.
你没事我很高兴
I'm glad you're okay.
甜蜜的家
Home, sweet home.
没有你我们就不是一家人了
We're not a family without you.
家
Home.
看看你
Look at you.
真不敢相信你独自在镇上到处跑
I can't believe you've been running around town all alone.
太可怕了
That's just awful.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
我尽力收拾干净了
I tried my best to tidy up.
你找到它了
You found her!
谢天谢地它没事
Thank goodness she's safe and sound.
真希望你没有那样跑掉  淑女  你把大家都吓坏了
Wish you hadn't run off like that, Lady. You upset everyone.
没关系  淑女
That's okay, Lady.
莎拉姑姑的意思是她很抱歉
What Aunt Sarah meant to say was she's sorry.
而且她要走了
And she was just leaving.
你知道吗
Well, you know what?
我正好有个
Just so happens that I do have
非常重要的约会
a very important engagement to attend to.
要是我的话  我会仔细考虑
You know, if I were you, I would think long and hard
要不要让那条狗靠近可爱的宝宝
about letting that dog get close to that sweet baby.
-下次我们可以...  -不会有下次了
- I mean, next time we can... - Oh, there won't be a next time.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你好大的胆子
How dare you!
好吧
Well...
莎拉姑姑说的
Aunt Sarah does have a point
让你靠近宝宝的话是有道理的
about letting you get close to the baby.
没事的  淑女  来吧
It's all right, Lady. Come on.
来吧  淑女  来吧
Come on, Lady. Come on.
淑女  这是露露
Lady, this is Lulu.
她现在也是家庭的一员了
She's part of the family now, too.
来吧
Go on.
真好
There you go.
你在玩吗
Are you playing?
一切都恢复正常是不是很棒
Isn't it nice to have everything back to normal?
穿着裙子的狗还好意思说
Says the dog in a dress.
老天在上  注意你的口水
Oh, for goodness sake, watch your drool!
我今天已经洗一次过澡了
I've already had a bath today.
我真的很想你们
I really missed you guys.
那吉姆和达令...
And things with Jim Dear and Darling are, uh...
我不是他们世界的中心了
Well, I'm not the center of their world anymore,
不过我们的世界变大了
but our world is just bigger.
仅此而已  我们有了露露
That's all. We have Lulu now.
听起来真操心
Sounds exhausting.
你不再流落街头我们就很高兴了
We're just glad you're off the street.
远离那条肮脏的流浪狗
Away from that dirty street dog.
是啊  我想你们没看错他
Yeah, guess you all were right about him.
不过也不全是坏事
Although it wasn't all bad.
流浪狗  他们和我们一样
You know, street dogs, they're just like us.
他们只是不够幸运  没有家
They just aren't lucky enough to have homes.
仅此而已
That's all.
所以你能回家真是太好了  不是吗
Then it's a darn good thing you made it back to yours, innit?
是啊
Yeah.
我无法想象街头生活
I cannot imagine life on the street!
争夺残羹剩饭填饱肚子
Scrappin' about for your next meal,
没有栅栏给你安全感
no fences to make you feel safe.
那是我能想象到的最奇怪的生活
It is the oddest, most bizarre life I can imagine.
乔克  杰奎琳
Jock! Jacqueline!
宫廷小丑准备好了吗
Who's ready to entertain the court?
叫我了  祝我好运吧[摔断腿]That's my cue. Hope I break a leg.
那就太遗憾了
Yeah, wouldn't that be a shame.
先生  别得寸进尺  别看我身材小  但我力量大
Don't push it, Mister. I may be small, but I am mighty.
欢迎你回家  淑女
Good to have you home, Lady.
瞧瞧这是谁
Look what the cat dragged in.
不好说  这家伙看起来太忧郁了  不像流浪汉
I don't know. This guy, he looks too blue to be the Tramp.
你们好  为什么你们戴着项圈
Hey, guys. Why are you wearing collars?
原来我们是可收养的
Turns out we're adoptable.
你们俩在这儿呢  希望你们饿了
There's my two. I hope you're hungry.
来吧
Here you go.
晚餐前的一点零食
Just a little snack before dinner.
什么
What?
别吃太饱  别走开
Save some room. Stay.
你相信吗
You believe that?
屠夫直接把骨头给他了
The butcher just gives it to him.
等等  等一下  你们俩被领养了
Wait, wait. Hang on. You two, adopted?
从来没想过你们会成为家养狗
Never really took you two for family dogs.
在某种程度上  我们一直都是家养狗
In a way, we've always been family dogs.
至少是彼此的家人
At least to each other.
这个世界是怎么了  大家都和人类生活在一起
What is the world coming to? Everybody's living with people!
别激动  你这么生气干什么
Easy. What're you so upset about?
这和我们在收容所遇到的
This wouldn't have anything to do with
那个姑娘没关系吧
that girl we met in the pound, would it?
什么  谁  淑女  你见过她吗
What? Who? Lady? But, did you meet her?
不  我没有在想她
No. I'm not thinking about her.
我好得很  真的特别好
I'm doing good. I'm doing really good!
你确定吗  你看起来可是一团糟
Are you sure? 'Cause you seem like you're doing terrible.
不  牛头  你搞错了  他好得很
No, Bull, you got it all wrong. He's doin' great.
他的梦想成真了  而且他说的都是对的
He got what he always wanted, and was right about everything.
我们看的是同一条狗吗
Are we looking at the same dog?
是啊  他可以自由自在
Yep. He's free to be himself,
-无牵无挂  -形影单只
- and free to be by himself. - By myself.
-我是不是搞砸了  -说得没错
- I screwed up, didn't I? - Yep, sure did.
怎么回事  佩吉
What's goin' on, Peg?
无所谓了
Doesn't matter. It's...
都太迟了
It's too late.
她的家人回来找她了
Her family came back for her.
你是说就像她回去找你一样
You mean like she did... for you?
天啊
Oh, man.
我得弥补这事  我不知道能不能做到
I gotta fix it. I don't know if I can,
但我得试试  我必须试试
but I... I gotta try. I have to.
-我们明白  -我不明白
- We get it. - I don't!
让她明白你的感受
Just let her know how you feel.
-好  -佩吉  解释一下刚才发生了什么
- Okay! - Peggy, fill me in. What just happened?
这个我要偷走  好吗
I'm stealing this, okay?
不好  你这个小偷
No, it's not okay! Thief!
世事难料啊  流浪汉来了
What do you know? It's the Tramp.
给你带了点东西
Brought you somethin'.
给你
Here.
专门为你挑的
Picked it out, special.
这也是你偷的吗
Did you steal that one, too?
不是
No.
这是礼物
It was a gift.
我借来的礼物
A borrowed gift that, um...
好吧  是我偷的
Okay, yep, I stole it.
听着
Look, um...
在火车场的时候
Back at the train yard...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry for, um...
我不应该离开你的
I never should've left your side.
你自己也说了
You said it yourself.
没有人是忠诚的  你为什么要忠诚呢
Nobody else is loyal, so why should you be?
我就应该相信你的
I should've just believed you.
不  你不应该相信我
No. You shouldn't have believed me.
无论我说过什么关于自由自在的话
Whatever I said about that, about, you know, being free and...
都不是真的
That was not true.
因为没有你的自由自在  就是...
Because being free without you there, now it's just...
就是形影单只
That's just... being alone.
你知道我是条流浪狗
Look, um, you know I'm a street dog.
我对谁都没有多大价值
And I don't have much value to anyone...
千万别这么说
Don't you say that.
对我来说你是有价值的
You have value to me.
我想你了
I missed you.
我也想你
Missed you, too.
有时候我晚上出来只是为了对着月亮嚎叫
Sometimes I come outside at night just to howl at the moon.
这个没必要停止
Well, that... That doesn't have to end.
我们可以一起嚎叫  一起自由奔跑
We could howl again. We can run free.
一起去更多的冒险
Have more adventures.
现在还为时不晚
It's... It's not too late for that.
是吧
Is it?
抱歉  但为时已晚
Sorry... but it is.
我属于这里  和吉姆
I belong here... with Jim Dear,
达令还有露露在一起  我们是一家人
and Darling, and Lulu. We're a family.
他们离不开我
They depend on me.
我对他们忠诚
And I'm loyal to them.
是啊  你是
Yeah, you're...
你是对的
You're right.
这是你应得的  淑女
You deserve it, Lady.
这也是你应得的
You deserve it, too.
你应该得到爱
You deserve love.
很遗憾不是和我
I'm just sorry that it can't be with me.
淑女  进屋来
Lady! Come inside.
我这就走
I'll go.
你应该和家人在一起
You belong with your family.
淑女  别在外面淋雨了
Lady! Come in out of the rain.
谁啊
It's...
露露
Lulu!
我要找的那条流浪狗曾经和你家的狗一起混
The stray I'm after was running around the streets with your dog.
-淑女  -淑女
- Lady! - Lady!
我知道它要来这里  你家的狗也知道
I know he's coming here. And she knows it, too!
-淑女  -没事的  这样吧
- Lady! - It's all right. You know what?
-别这样  -我让它去冷静一下  过来
- No. Please. - I'm gonna let her calm down. Come on.
很显然这就是它叫个不停的原因
That's obviously why she's barking.
好了好了  没事的
There, there. It's all right.
不  实际上我认为
No, actually I think she's still
它对收容的经历心有余悸
upset about her experience at the pound.
很明显它在那里一点教训也没长
Well, clearly she learned nothing from her time there.
一会就好  淑女
Just for a minute, Lady.
力气真大
So strong. She...
淑女
Lady?
这么晚了  还好我们听到敲门声了
It's so late. It's a good thing we heard the door.
-我们正准备睡觉呢  -是啊
- We were about to get into bed. - Oh, yeah.
没错  夫人  事关安全不能等到早上
It sure is, ma'am. Safety can't wait till morning.
淑女
Lady?
淑女  是我
Lady? It's me!
谢天谢地  你回来了
Thank goodness! You came back!
你没事吧  出什么事了
Are you okay? What's wrong?
露露的房间里有只老鼠  但我出不去
There's a rat in Lulu's room. But I can't get out of here.
-我来处理  -真的吗
I'll take care of it. You will?
好  不过小心  捕狗人在屋里
Okay. But be careful. The dog catcher's in there.
别担心  交给我
Don't worry. I got this.
快点
Hurry!
我已经追踪这条流浪狗好几个小时了
I've been tracking this street dog for hours.
就算它现在还没到  很快也会来
If he isn't here already, he will be.
这就是你之前在找的那条流浪狗吗
This is the same stray that you were looking for before?
正是那条
The very one.
你还没抓到它吗
And you still haven't caught him?
那边是你家后院吗
Is that the back of your property?
什么  那请进吧
What... What... Please, come right in.
等一下
What's... Hold on.
什么  抱歉
What? I'm sorry.
你确定它朝我家来了吗
And you're sure he's headed this way?
确定  为了你们的安全  我最好在这里等它
Yes. And for your safety, I better wait for him.
你最好泡点咖啡
And you'd better make some coffee.
吉姆  你听到了
Jim, you heard the man.
马上就来  达令
Right away, Darling.
只有咖啡没有蛋糕可不行
Coffee without cake is the devil's work.
楼上发生什么了
What is going on up there?
我跟你说  我差点
I'm telling you, I had him...
就把它抓起来了
inches from custody.
别忘了  这条狗浑身生疮
And keep in mind, this dog is mangy,
肮脏不堪  非常危险
dirty, dangerous.
滚开
Get off me!
不  离宝宝远点
No! Stay away from the baby!
不
No!
在审判中...
In the trial...
你没事
You're okay.
等等  那是露露吗
Wait, is that Lulu?
天啊
Oh, God.
露露
Lulu?
滚开  离她远点
Get away! Get away from her!
别过来  退后  退后
All right, stay back! Get back! Back up!
-露  -它在这儿
- Lu! - He's here!
-露露  -去抱孩子
- Lulu! - Get the baby!
-她没事吧  -我不知道
- Is she all right? - I don't know!
别动  别动
Stay! Stay!
没事了  它在这儿  狗在这儿
We're okay. He's here! The dog's here!
你们逃过一劫
You got very lucky there.
这家伙真是个祸害
This one's a real menace.
小心  你确定抓牢了吗
Careful. Are you sure you've got him?
别担心  它跑不掉了
Don't worry. He's not going anywhere.
流浪狗收容所
真奇怪  我以前从没见过这条狗
This is so strange. I've never seen this dog before in my life.
我不知道它是怎么进去的
I'm not sure how he could've got inside.
狗是很危险的
Dogs can be dangerous.
这种事正是我们这行想要防范的
This is exactly the kinda thing we try to prevent in my profession.
当然
Of course.
不过我得说
You know, I must say, I...
一开始我没把你当回事
I didn't take you seriously at first.
经常有人这么说
I get that a lot.
不过现在你安全了
But you're safe now.
它不在街上游荡了
He's off the streets,
而如何处理袭击人类的狗
and we've got strict rules on what happens
我们有严格的规定
to dogs that attack humans.
非常感谢你抽出时间
Well, thank you very much for your time.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
你听到那边的骚动了吗
Did you hear all that ruckus?
你真的觉得他要伤害小宝宝吗
Do you really think he went after the wee baby?
我从没信任过他
I never trusted him,
但我也从没想过他会那么做
but I never thought he'd do that.
淑女  我很抱歉
Lady, I'm so sorry.
你只是想警告我们小心那条狗
You were just trying to warn us about that dog...
淑女  淑女
Lady! Lady!
淑女
Lady?
Lady!
淑女
怎么了
What?
达令
Darling!
吉姆  过来
Jim, come here!
怎么了
What?
天啊  是什么
Oh, God. What is it?
是只老鼠
It's a... It's a rat.
不  我...
Oh, no. I've...
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
捕狗人带他去监狱了
Dog catcher took him to the pokey.
-我得拦下他们  -怎么回事
- I've gotta stop them! - What happened?
是老鼠
It was the rat!
老信  也许我们看错他了
Trusty! Maybe we misjudged him.
淑女没看错  我们得帮她
Lady didn't. We gotta help her.
穿着苏格兰裙我跑不起来
I can't run in my kilt!
你得试试
You're gonna have to try.
不
Oh, no!
它要干什么
What is she doing?
-淑女  -淑女
- Lady! - Lady!
-淑女  -我们去追它
- Lady! - Let's go get her!
我们去追它  快点
Let's go get her. Come on.
快点
Come on!
我们得拦下那辆马车
We've gotta stop that wagon.
我不是跑得快的品种好吗
I'm not built for speed, you know?
你能做到的  小狗
You can do it, little doggie.
我的小短腿
My wee legs!
所有人都认为我疯了
Everyone thought I was crazy.
现在我可不像疯子了吧
But I don't look so crazy now, do I?
快点  继续跑
Come on! Keep going!
老天啊  我在裸奔
In the name of the wee man! I'm naked.
不  是跑得更快了
Nah, you're just faster.
它是怎么了
What has gotten into her?
它为什么要追那条流浪狗
Why would she be chasing that stray?
吉姆  露露没事
Jim, Lulu's fine.
我们真的看到那条狗袭击她了吗
Did we actually see that dog attack her?
看到了
Yes!
没看到
No?
-他们往哪边走了  -我没看见
- Which way did they go? - I didn't see it!
别担心  寻血猎犬以鼻代目
Fear not, the bloodhound sees with his snout.
又来了
Not this again!
你能做到的  老信  我们相信你
You can do it, Trusty. We believe in you.
我们没时间玩这个
We've no got time for this!
安静  我听不见自己的鼻子了
Quiet! I can't hear myself smell.
这是属于你的时刻  老信
This is your moment, Trusty.
加油  靠得住
Come on, Ol' Reliable.
你能做到的  老信
You can do it, Trusty.
我有发现
I got somethin'.
鲷鱼  见鬼
Snapper! Darn it!
抱歉  淑女  我错了
Sorry, Lady, I'm wrong.
事实是  靠得住老了  靠不住了
Truth is, Ol' Reliable is old and not that reliable.
老信  你给我听好了
Trusty! Now you listen to me!
把注意力集中在我身上
I want you to focus on me.
我短暂的一生中  有一半的时间都在听你
I have not listened to you witter on about "Ol' Reliable"
喋喋不休地念叨"靠得住"
for half of my short life
可不是让你在紧要关头放弃的
just to see you quit when we need you!
如果我能用这四条小短腿
Now if I can run through the streets
在街上裸奔
stark naked with these wee, tiny legs,
你就能闻到马车里的狗
you can smell a dog in a wagon!
麻溜地
Now, do it!
遵命  女士
Yes, ma'am.
调动技能  寻血猎犬
Use your skills, bloodhound!
加油
Come on.
香蕉皮  垃圾
Banana peel... Trash...
-你能做到的  老信  -猫粪
- You can do it, Trusty. - Cat dung.
用力闻
Smell hard!
流浪狗收容所
我做到了
I did it?
我做到了  这边  快点
I did it! This way. Come on!
-快点  -又开跑了
- Come on! - Well. Here we go.
看  就在那里  老信  你做到了
Look, there it is, Trusty! You did it!
靠得住再获成功
Ol' Reliable strikes again!
我从来没有怀疑过你
I never doubted you for a second!
快  从这里走
Come on! Through here!
淑女
Lady...
不  你在干什么
No! What are you doing?
快点
Come on!
别担心  我们来救你了
Don't worry, we're gonna save you.
淑女  不  太危险了
Lady! No! It's too dangerous.
市政流浪狗收容所
你这疯狗  你在干什么
You crazy dog. What are you doing?
放松
Easy!
慢点
Slow down!
放松  放松
Easy! Easy!
快点
Come on!
我的腿跑不了更快了
My legs can't go any quicker!
抱歉  淑女
Sorry, Lady...
不  我们要被甩掉了
Oh, no! We're losing them.
淑女  不
Lady! No!
不  不不不
No! No, no, no! No!
不
Oh, no.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
醒醒  你没事的
Come on. You're okay.
起来
Get up.
醒醒  求你了
Come on. Please?
醒醒
Just wake up.
求你了
Please?
你不能死
You can't go.
我们还有地方要去  还要去冒险
We... have places to go, adventures to... take.
醒醒  求你了
Just wake up. Please?
挺不错  小鬼
Pretty good, kid.
不过我们得在你的音量上下点功夫
We still need to work on your volume.
好的
Okay.
他没事
He's okay.
我可能要晕倒了
I think I might faint.
-发生什么了  -不  淑女
- What happened? - Oh, no! Lady!
淑女
Lady!
它受伤了吗
Is she hurt?
-没事了  没事了  -抱歉
- It's okay. It's okay. - Sorry.
-没事了  我们没事  -吉姆  它在流血
- It's all right. We're okay. - Jim, he's bleeding.
他为了保护露露  和老鼠打斗时受伤了
He got hurt protecting Lulu from the rat.
怎么会这样
How'd this happen?
过来  你还是得跟我走
Come on. You're still coming with me.
吉姆
Jim?
淑女  没事的
Lady, it's all right.
-冷静  冷静  -放开它
- Calm down, calm down. - Let him go!
我不管要付出什么代价
I don't care what it takes.
就算步行我也要把你送去收容所
I'll walk you to the pound if I have to.
什么  好吧
What? Okay. Okay.
-我们得做点什么  -好的
- We have to do something. - Okay.
停下  住手  你不能这么做
Stop! Stop it! You can't do this!
什么  它袭击了你们的孩子
What? He was attacking your baby!
不对  它保护了我们的孩子
No, he was protecting our baby.
夫人  没有许可证无家可归的狗
Ma'am, any unlicensed dog without a home
要被立即抓进收容所
will be immediately impounded!
它...
He...
它有家
He has a home.
它是流浪狗
He's a street dog!
它不是  它有家
No, he's not. He has a home.
什么
What?
这是我们的狗  先生
That's our dog, sir.
它要跟我们回家
He's coming home with us.
过来  狗狗
Come here, boy.
伙计
Buddy.
-过来  -伙计
- Come here. - Hey, buddy.
-过来  过来  -没事的
- Come here. Come on. - It's okay.
没事的  过来
It's all right. Come on.
乖狗狗
Good boy.
来  好多了
There. That's better.
你没事了  狗狗
You're okay now, boy.
谢谢你帮助露露
Thank you for helping Lulu.
真是条乖狗狗
What a good boy.
我刚想到我要送你什么节日礼物了
I just figured out what I'm gettin' you for the holidays.
尊严
Dignity.
乔克阿姨  来和我们一起玩
Auntie Jock, come play with us!
这都是谁啊
Well, who do we have here?
这个造型我喜欢
Now this is a look I approve of.
谢谢  老信
Thank you, Trusty.
他们来自收容所
They're from the pound.
淑女的新朋友给了莎莉启发
Sally was inspired by Lady's new friend.
一开始我还有所保留  不过就像淑女说的
I wasn't so sure at first but, you know, it's like Lady said,
"我们的世界更大了"
"Our world is bigger now."
我必须承认
And I must admit,
他们非常非常柔软
they are... very, very soft.
学员们  我是老信叔叔
Cadets. I'm your Uncle Trusty.
你好  老信叔叔
Hi, Uncle Trusty.
你们想听一个靠得住的故事吗
Y'all wanna hear a tale of Ol' Reliable?
我闻到捕狗人的那次
About the time I sniffed out a dog catcher?
用善良的心救了一条可怜的流浪狗
Saved a poor stray with a heart of gold.
想听  给我们讲讲  老信叔叔
Yeah! Tell us, Uncle Trusty.
是啊  给我们讲讲
Yeah, tell us.
围过来  小狗们
Gather around, pups.
好
Yay.
靠得住的故事
Story of a Ol' Reliable.
不对  是靠得住
No. Old Reliable.
好了  这是给谁的礼物呢
Okay. I wonder who this one is for?
看啊
Look at that.
快看啊  是什么
Look at that. What is it?
过来  狗狗  是时候正式宣布了
Come here, boy. It's time we made you official.
看啊
Look at that.
-欢迎来到我们家  -好了
- Welcome to the family. - There you go.
你觉得怎么样  淑女
What do you think, Lady?
喜欢吗
Yeah?
喜欢吗  露
Yeah, Lu?
你把露露的礼物打开吧
Why don't you open Lulu's present?
看看你  戴着项圈
Look at you with a collar.
几乎像是一条家养狗了
You almost look like a family dog.
你能相信吗
Can you believe it?
对我来说  你永远都是流浪汉
Well, you'll always be the Tramp to me.
感觉怎么样
So, how does it feel?
感觉有点...
You know, it kinda feels...
怎么  太紧了  太痒了
What, too tight? Too itchy?
不
No...
可能需要花点时间适应
Might take some gettin' used to.
我是想说  感觉有点
Was gonna say, it kinda feels, um...
像家
like home.
♪ 夜晚寂静如雪 ♪
♪ Silent as the snowflake in the night ♪
♪ 神圣的夜晚 ♪
♪ Holy is the spirit of this night ♪
♪ 世界一片祥和 ♪
♪ All the world is calm and peaceful ♪
♪ 世界一片欢乐 ♪
♪ All the world is bright and joyful ♪
♪ 爱之精神 ♪
♪ Spirit of love ♪
♪ 和平之子 ♪
♪ And child of peace ♪
♪ 爱无止境 ♪
♪ Love unending ♪
♪ 永不停息 ♪
♪ That shall not cease ♪
♪ 和平  我友善的孩子们 ♪
♪ Peace, my children of goodwill ♪
♪ 和平  我的孩子们 ♪
♪ Peace, my children ♪
♪ 和平  安稳 ♪
♪ Peace, be still ♪
剧终
♪ 两次就很好 ♪
♪ Two times is good ♪
♪ 两倍的美丽 ♪
♪ Twice the beauty ♪
♪ 两倍的乐趣  比一次多 ♪
♪ Twice the fun, more than for once ♪
♪ 因为内心深处  我们正在酝酿 ♪
♪ 'Cause inside, we're cooking up ♪
♪ 一生的冒险 ♪
♪ A lifetime of adventures ♪
♪ 胡闹与浪漫 ♪
♪ Mischief and romance ♪
♪ 太美好了 ♪
♪ That's the good stuff ♪
♪ 知足常乐 ♪
♪ That's enough ♪
♪ 别管你的血统 ♪
♪ Never mind your pedigree ♪
♪ 你和我  宝贝  我们是一对 ♪
♪ You and me, babe, that's a match ♪
♪ 让我们创造新的记忆 ♪
♪ Let's make new memories ♪
♪ 想想我们能构思的计划 ♪
♪ Think of schemes that we can hatch ♪
♪ 化腐朽为神奇 ♪
♪ Make magic out of simple things ♪
♪ 几根骨头  我们的家  还有几条小狗 ♪
♪ A few bones, our home and some pups ♪
♪ 太美好了 ♪
♪ That's the good stuff ♪
♪ 知足常乐 ♪
♪ That's enough ♪
♪ 我在想 ♪
♪ So, I was thinking ♪
♪ 如果你和我能休息一天的话 ♪
♪ If you and I could take the day off ♪
♪ 去镇上我们最喜欢的地方转转 ♪
♪ Go around town, visit some of our favorite spots ♪
♪ 因为什么也比不上 ♪
♪ 'Cause there's nothing like ♪
♪ 你我一起消磨时间 ♪
♪ Spending time together, you know, you and I ♪
♪ 我们去惹点大麻烦怎么样 ♪
♪ How about we get into some big trouble? ♪
♪ 你知道是哪种麻烦 ♪
♪ You know that kind of trouble ♪
♪ 来吧 ♪
♪ Come on, yeah ♪
♪ 从没这么好过 ♪
♪ Better than ever now ♪
♪ 我们对着月亮嚎叫 ♪
♪ While we're howling at the moon ♪
♪ 感觉所向披靡 ♪
♪ Feeling invincible ♪
♪ 因为你和我  我们是一伙的 ♪
♪ 'Cause you and me, we're in cahoots ♪
♪ 唯一的美中不足 ♪
♪ Now, the thing that I would switch up ♪
♪ 有些黑猫我就是看不上 ♪
♪ Some black cat couldn't change my love ♪
♪ 有我在  宝贝 ♪
♪ I got you, babe ♪
♪ 我们拥有彼此 ♪
♪ We've got each other now ♪
♪ 太美好了 ♪
♪ That's the good stuff ♪
♪ 知足常乐 ♪
♪ That's enough ♪